Floyd S. Fierman papers, ca. 1850-1997 (bulk: 1870 - 1970)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series I: New Mexico’s Jewish History
  - Ilfeld, Louis. (Box 2, Folder 51)
    Article - Meyer, Beatrice Ilfeld, "Don Luis Ilfeld"(1973).
  - Ilfeld, Ludwig. (Box 2, Folder 52)
    Article - (Hawkins, Leona) "Subsequent Voyage: April 21, 1874-May 29, 1960."
    Oral history of Ludwig William Ilfeld.
    Copies of several photographs.
    Obituary for Ludwig W. Ilfeld (April 31, 1960).
    Correspondence from Holly Smith (University of Arizona) to Frederick Ilfeld (July 8, 1995).
    Correspondence from Fredric Ilfeld to Abraham Chanin (September 15, 1993).
    Article -"Fire Company 100 Years Old," by Mick Nickel (May 16, 1982).
  - Jacobs, Rabbi Pizer: Article - (Goldenstein, R.) "American Judaism in the Making" (June 1923). (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Jaffa family (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 54)
    Court papers concerning cases against Benjamin Arthur Jaffa (1931).
    Book excerpt - (Simons, Marc) Albuquerque: A Narrative History (University of New Mexico Press, 1982).
    Copy of the report of the meeting of creditors of Jaffa Prager and Company (September 26, 1921).
    Book excerpt - (Fleming, E. E. and M. J. Hoffman, ed.) Round up on the Pecos (1978).
    Correspondence from the archivist at the Chaves County Historical Society to F. Fierman (October 21, 1985).
    Correspondence from Hebrew Union College to Rabbi Marcus (October 31, 1984).
    Genealogy of the Jaffa family compiled by Lou R. Strauss.
    Correspondence from Nathan Jaffa to El Capitan Livestock Company (December 28, 1908).
    Correspondence from Lou R. Strauss to Rabbi F. Fierman (1983).
    Notes on the Jaffa family written by F. Fierman.
    Genealogy of the Philip L. Strauss branch of the Rosenwald family tree.
    Article - "The Pecos Valley Development Number of the Roswell Evening News."
    Correspondence from the archivist at the Chaves County Historical Society, Inc. to F. Fierman (June 8, 1985).
    Article - "Recognize Work of David Weinman at Cemetery."
    Copy of obituaries for Nathan Jaffa.
    Brief biography of Joseph H. Jaffa.
    Articles which include discussion of several Masonic orders. Reference to Nathan Jaffa.
    Copy of a list of life members of the Elks Club. Nathan Jaffa is listed.
    Copy of lists of several committees and their members for the New Mexico Bankers Association (1924).
    Copy of the resources and liabilities inventory of the Bank of Commerce of Roswell, New Mexico (April 3, 1923).
    Copy of correspondence from Nathan Jaffa to J.F. Hinkly (May 30, 1891).
    Copy of the inventory of papers and photographs of Dr. Adele S. Jaffa.
    Copy of correspondence from Arthur to Joe in regard to a deed (July 26, 1921).
    Correspondence from the archivist at Chaves County Historical Museum to F. Fierman (May 28, 1985).
    Several deeds of trust and quit claim deeds issued to members of the Jaffa family (1890's).
  - Jaffa family (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 55)
    Contract between L. Freudenthal and Leonora Jaffa (signed March 24, 1899).
    Inventories for the White House Mercantile Co.
    Inventory and correspondences from the Simon Sanders and Co. (1877-1878).
    Correspondence from S. Gregory and Son to J. Jaffa (January 3, 1917).
    Last Will and Testament of Leonora Jaffa (November 6, 1898).
    Legal contracts and papers dealing with the purchase of land.
    Article with discussion of Congregation Aaron.
    Obituary for Sol H. Jaffa (December 1, 1941).
    Two obituaries for Sol H. Jaffa.
    Obituary for Dr. Perry Jaffa.
    Article - "Notice of Hearing of Petition to Sell Real Estate" (August 9, 1921).
    Receipt for payment received by the Jaffa Brothers (1894).
    Article - "Arthur Prager Paid Tribute For Service" (September 1965).
  - Jaffa family (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Jaffa, Henry: Article - "A New Mexican In Washington" (June 11, 1959). (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Jewish Artists: Article - (Milstein, T.)"Gallery to Host Sukkot Show" (September 1996). (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Jewish Community Center (Albuquerque): Article - (Milstein, T.) "Public Talk Resumes About Albuquerque JCC" (February 1997). (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Jewish Family Service (Albuquerque): Article - (Milstein, T.) "JFS Forming Chevra Kaddisha To Provide Burial Rituals" (September 1996). (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Jewish Federation (Albuquerque). (Box 2, Folder 61)
    Three articles discussing fundraising for a new Jewish Community Center in Albuquerque (1995).
    Article provides discussion of the improved Jewish Family Services.
    Pamphlet with information on Jewish Family Services.
    Article - (Milstein, T.) "JFGA To Unveil Memorial Plan, Music" (November 1996).
    Article - (Milstein, T.) "JFGA Begins CJF Pilot Project To Create Endowment Program" (November 1996).
    Article - (Milstein, T.) "Music Travels Almost 60 Years For Premiere" (November 1996).
    Article - (Milstein, T.) "JCC Has Long History in Albuquerque" (March, 1997).
    Article - (Neumann, Cora) "A Documentary to Uncover Jewish New Mexico" (July/August, 1997).
    Article - (Milstein, T.) "A Memorial Controversy Prompts Public Meeting" (September, 1997).
    Two articles about the proposed Holocaust memorial and the controversy surrounding it.
    Article - (Milstein, T.) "A Board Decision Made, Strong Feelings Still Exist" (November, 1997).
    Article - "A Retreat Offers Jewish Leaders Chance to Open Dialogue" by C. Newmann (November, 1997).
  - Jews of New Mexico. (Box 2, Folder 62)
    Article - (Goldenstein, R.) "American Judaism in the Making" (June 22, 1923).
    Article - "Carving Out an Identity in the Land of 'Anglos'" (November 1, 1989).
    Article - (Parish, William J.) "The German Jew and the Commercial Revolution in Territorial New Mexico (University of New Mexico, Sixth Annual Research Lecture; May 1, 1959).
    Article excerpt - "The German Jew," New Mexico Historical Review.
    Handwritten notes on Alexander William Doniphan written by F. Fierman.
    Original, handwritten statistics of population, marriage, birth, traders, and merchants in New Mexico, 1845-1900.
  - Kahn, Gustav: Kahn, Gustav - "Gustav Kahn and the Kahn Family: Memoirs of Gustav Kahn, of Santa Fe, New Mexico; Recollections of a New Mexico Merchant" (Santa Fe, New Mexico; 1964). (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Klein family. (Box 2, Folder 64)
    Resume of Howard Klein (Las Cruces, New Mexico).
    Handwritten biographies on the family history of Bernise and Howard Klein (October 12, 1991).
  - Klein, Rabbi Joseph: Article - (Dickinson, LaVerne) "The Lone Rabbi of Las Cruces" (November 2, 1982). (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Klein, Sam: Obituary for Samuel Klein (1952). (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Krohn, Rabbi A.Lincoln. (Box 2, Folder 67)
    Correspondence from F.M. to A.L. Krohn (September 27, 1938).
    Copy of correspondence from Krohn to the Albuquerque Public Library (November 30 1938).
    Copy of correspondence from A.L. Krohn to Mr. Shaffer (November 29, 1938).
    Copy of correspondences from the U.S. senate to A.L. Krohn (1937-1938).
    Copy of correspondence from A.L. Krohn to Dr. Wise (January 13, 1938).
    Correspondence from A.L. Krohn to Seigfried Seligman (December 18, 1937).
    Correspondence from Krohn to the members of the Middle Rio Grande Joint Farmers Committee (December 39, 1937).
    Correspondence from Krohn to Dr. Wise (December 17, 1937).
    Correspondence from Emil Schram to A.L. Krohn (September 17, 1938).
    A prayer which discusses Roosevelt, the New Deal, and farmers (author and source unknown).
  - Krupp, Haymon (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Krupp, Haymon (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Laguna, NM: Interview with Wallace Gunn (September 24, 1989). (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Las Cruces, NM. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Selections from the Dona Ana County Outsize Record Books Inventory, and Dona Ana County District Court Records (1981).
    A page from the newspaper The Border (Thursday, April 13, 1871).
    Several pages from the newspaper The Border (Thursday April 6, 1871).
    Article - (Morris, Joan) "The Real Matriarch of the Mesilla" (May 10, 1988).
    F. Fierman's notes on business and real estate in Las Cruces and Dona Ana.
    Pamphlet - "Stahmann Farms, Inc. Las Cruces, New Mexico, Diversified Farming."
  - Laski, Reverend Samuel M.: Article - "Reluctant Pilgrims," New Mexico Magazines (October 1982). (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Las Vegas, NM. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Brochures on Las Vegas.
    Article - (Kramer, W. M.) "My Shtetele California."
    Article - (Martinez, Demetria) "Heritage of Jews Marked in Stone" (February 21, 1987).
    Brochure - "Stones of Remembrance: The Historic Jewish Cemetery in Las Vegas, New Mexico" (New Mexico Jewish Historical Society).
  - Latz, Benjamin. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Copy of correspondence from J. Latz to Rabbi A. Shinedling (September 30, 1966 and June 30, 1967).
    Copy of document which states the honorable discharge of B. Latz from the army (June 22, 1847).
    Original correspondences from J. Latz to F. Fierman in regard to information on Benjamin Latz (October 12, 1964 and January 15, 1965).
    Copy of document and correspondence in regard to Benjamin Latz's claim to Bounty Land (June 23, 1847 and January 29, 1852).
    Article excerpt - "History of Stanislaus County" (George Tinkham; 1921).
    Copy of correspondence from J. Latz to Rabbi J, Marcus (April 9, 1970).
    Copy of correspondence from Robert Levinson to J. Latz (June 12, 1967).
    Correspondence from the San Francisco Civic Center to J. Latz (March 9, 1966).
    Genealogy of burials of the Latz family (compiled by Jacob Latz).
    Correspondence from Jacob Latz to Rabbi Marcus (September 8, 1968).
    Copy of the Affidavit of Identity from the State of Louisiana for Benjamin Latz (June 4, 1847).
    Copies of legal documents and correspondence concerning Benjamin Latz's application for a land warrant certificate (1850-52).
    Legal document concerning Benjamin Latz's service in the Mexican War.
  - Leitensdorfer, John. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Article - "The Remarkable Life and Adventures of John Eugene Leitensdorfer."
    F. Fierman's notes on the Leitensdorfer family.
    Article - (Taylor, Morris F.) "The Leitensdorfer Claim in the Vigil and St. Vrain Grant" (1980).
    Manuscript notes from a manuscript dealing with the Leitensdorfer family.
  - Lesinsky, Henry: Article - "A New Mexican In Washington" (June 11, 1959). (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Levenson, Fannie and Sherman: Outline of an interview with Fanny and Sherman Levenson (December 7, 1989). (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Levy, NM: F. Fierman's notes on Levy, New Mexico (one page). (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Lindauer, Herman: Obituary for Herman Lindauer (December 1968). (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Lindauer, Sigmund. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Manuscript by F. Fierman - "Lindauer Family."
    Article (Inmon, Thelma) "Early Luna Politics Still Worth a Mention" (April 8, 1980).
    Article - "Land of Early History Donated to Boy Scouts."
    Article - "Deming's Founders Planned to Make it 'New Chicago'" (November 8, 1938).
    Original correspondence from Herman Lindauer to F. Fierman (January 3, 1951).
    Article excerpt - "Ghosts Walk in Georgetown" (March 1935).
    Article excerpt - "Old Man Lindauer" (March 28, 1935).
    Article "S. Lindauer" (1901).
    Brief biography of Sigmund Lindauer, with photograph.
    Copy of photograph of Sigmund Lindauer.
  - Loewenstein, Benjamin: Goldenstein, R. - "American Judaism in the Making" (June 1923). (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Loewenstein and Strousse. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Correspondence from Sidney Loewenstein to William J. Parish (February 27, 1962).
    Correspondence from Sidney Loewenstein to the president of University of New Mexico (February 19, 1962).
    F. Fierman's notes which list some of the inventory of the State Records Center and Archives on Correspondence from Arthur Obermayer to William Parish (May 18, 1963; includes response).
    Copy of inventories from the Loewenstein and Strousse Company (Mora, New Mexico).
  - Los Alamos, NM: Article - (Sperling, Paul) "Jews of Early Los Alamos A Memoir" (July 1986). (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Maisel: Article - (Goldenstein, R.) "American Judaism in the Making" (June 1923). (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Mandell, Michael: Correspondence from Gladys Mandell Epstein to E.F. Castetter. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Marx, Cantor Jacqueline: "A Cantor Joins Albuquerque Congregation in its Love Song" (by C. Neumann; November, 1997). (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Mashbir, Frieda. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Article - "Reminiscences of Frieda Freudenthal Mashbir" (F. Fierman).
    Autobiography of Frieda Mashbir (July 7, 1925).
  - Mayer, Henry: Biography of Henry Mayer. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Meyer, Jacob: Obituary for Jacob Meyer (December 12, 1990). (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Meyers, Ernest: Article - (Goldenstein, R.) "American Judaism in the Making" (June 1923). (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Mills, Rabbi Steve: Article - "Link Cartoonist First in Nation" (September, 1997). (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Moise family. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Resolution of the respect upon the death of Columbus Moise.
    Copy of application for a license to sell merchandise (August 31, 1903). Requested by J.J. Moise.
    Biography of Julius J. Moise.
    Correspondence from the archivist at the State Records Center and Archives in New Mexico to F. Fierman concerning information of Julius and Sigmund Moise (June 5, 1980).
  - Mora, NM. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    F. Fierman's notes from the 1880 Mora census population schedules (written on note cards).
    Copy of correspondence from Ken Wells to Rabbi Malcolm Stern (May 9, 1959).
    A page of notes on Mora, New Mexico written by F. Fierman.
    Correspondence from Henry Ballin to Dr. Marcus (November, 1, 1951).
    Copy of court papers for the case of the Loewenstein Strousse and Company vs. the County of Mora (1894).
    Correspondence from Leon Obermayer to F. Fierman concerning Obermayer's family history (October 25, 1965).
    Original correspondence from Rosa Weiscopf to F. Fierman (October 6, 1950).
    Copy of correspondence from F. Fierman to the county clerk of Mora County New Mexico (September 19, 1980).
  - Nahm family. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Advertisement for Milton Nahm's book entitled Las Vegas and Uncle Joe: The New Mexico I Remember.
    Article - "A New Mexican in Washington" (June 11, 1959).
    Correspondence from Ruth and Milton Nahm to F. Fierman (1950, 1961, and 1965).
  - New Mexico Acoma Pueblo. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Copy of court records from the case Pueblo of Acoma vs. Juan Pedro Garbisu (1854).
    Correspondence from the archivist at the State Records Center and Archives in New Mexico to F. Fierman with regard to information on the case of the Pueblo of Acoma vs. Juan Pedro Garbisu (May 27, 1988).
    F. Fierman's attempt to translate the court records from the case of the Pueblo of Acoma vs. Juan Pedro Garbisu.
  - New Mexico (annual report, 1865): Transcription of the annual report of the territorial secretary (Hervisurpicy). (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - New Mexico (business directory). (Box 3, Folder 29)
    Court papers referring to the case of Joseph A. Gonzales and Joyce Gonzales vs. four groups of defendants (August 1983).
    Selected pages from the New Mexico State Business Directory (1920).
  - New Mexico (census): F. Fierman's notes taken from the 1850-1872 New Mexico census. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - New Mexico (government). (Box 3, Folder 31)
    List of Spanish and Mexican governors and captain-generals of New Mexico (1598-1846).
    Article - (Bullock, Alice) "Did the Hebrews Settle Ancient New Mexico?" (January 1976).
  - New Mexico (history). (Box 3, Folder 32)
    Article - (Ayers, John) "A Soldier's Experience in New Mexico."
    "Original Illustrated Map of the Great Southwest and Key to Indian Symbols" (by Fred Harvey).
    Correspondence from R.E. White to F. Fierman (May 12, 1952).
    Correspondence from Jessie Smith to F. Fierman (September 8, 1950).
    F. Fierman's notes on Silver City, New Mexico.
    F. Fierman's notes on Taos, Las Vegas, and Springer, New Mexico.
    Correspondence from W.A. Keleher to F. Fierman (September 15, 1950).
    Pamphlet - (Walter, Paul A.F.) "No. 31, Colonel Jose Francisco Chaves 1833-1904."
    Correspondence from the archivist at the State Records Center and Archives to F. Fierman (April 7, 1978).
    Book excerpt - El Gringo (W.W.H. Davis; 1938).
    Copy of the National Register of Historic Places Inventory, Nomination Form (1974).
    Excerpt - Confederate Government in Dona Ana County (by Charles S. Walker, Jr.).
    Excerpt - "Social Forces" (Southern Sociological Society: N.C.; 1962).
    Article - "The Historical Society of New Mexico" (by Ira G. Clarke).
    Book excerpt - New Mexico: Land of Many Cultures (by Frank D. Reeve).
    Article - "History of the Southwest: Personalities and Discoveries" (by Eleanor B. Adams).
    Selected excerpts relating to the "Lady in Blue."
    Notes written by F. Fierman in regard to the Colonial period of the New Mexico (1600's).
    Article - "The Jews of Albuquerque: A Southwestern Community" (by Morris Freedman; 1959).
  - New Mexico Jewish Historical Society. (Box 3, Folder 33)
    The New Mexico Jewish Historical Society Newsletter (1988-1995).
    Announcement for New Mexico Jewish Historical Society's ninth annual conference.
    Announcement for New Mexico Jewish Historical Society's tenth annual conference.
    List of New Mexico Historical Society roster of the board of directors.
    Announcement released in regard to the exhibit entitled "The Holocaust and New Mexico Jewish History: Contrasting Themes of Persecution and Tolerance."
    Pamphlet - "Making History: Contributions of Jewish Artists in New Mexico" (November 1993).
    Handwritten notes on Jewish women from New Mexico.
  - New Mexico Jewish Link. (Box 3, Folder 34)
    Advertisement which announces locations where the newsletter is available.
    Article - "New Year Bringing New Newspaper Name" (September 1996).
  - New Mexico (Jewish merchants): Article - (Robinson, Sherry) "The Promised Land" (April 22, 1990). (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - New Mexico (Jewish organizations). (Box 3, Folder 36)
    Paper - Robert E. Rosenwald, "Early Covered Wagon and Far West Days" (1982).
    Copy of correspondence from Jacob S. Raisin to David Winternitz (December 14, 1915).
    Report of the Council of Jewish Women of Las Vegas, New Mexico (1923).
    Contract between Congregation Montefiore and Dr. M. Lefkowitz (June 1905).
    Report of the building committee on the Jewish Temple (Las Vegas).
    Treasurers receipt from Congregation Montefiore (June 6, 1916).
    Signatures and amounts promised for the building of Congregation Montefiore (January 1886).
    Insurance document insuring the trustees of Montefiore Congregation (February 1917).
    Members list and minutes of the Las Vegas section of the Council of Jewish Women (Sept. 29; year unknown).
    Order of B'nai B'rith acknowledging a receipt (1914).
    Inventory of Las Vegas Bible Church.
    Acknowledgment from the National Committee for the Relief of Sufferers by Russian Massacres (1916).
    Miscellaneous documents from the city of Las Vegas.
    Documents which refer to early years of Congregation Montefiore (1865-1910).
    Abstract of the title to the Jewish cemetery and the Las Vegas Lodge Cemetery in Las Vegas (April 17, 1880).
    Specifications of the work and materials required in the completion of Congregation Montefiore.
    Indenture between Las Vegas Lodge No. 4 and the trustees of Las Vegas Lodge No. 4 in regard to the selling of property (May 14, 1902).
    Drawing of cemetery plot Las Vegas, New Mexico.
  - New Mexico (Jewish pioneers): Article - "A New Mexican in Washington" (June 11, 1959). (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - New Mexico (Jews and Indians): Article - "Indians and Jews: New Mexico and America" (by Gordon Bronitsky). (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - New Mexico (Jews of). (Box 3, Folder 39)
    Book excerpt - (La Farge, Oliver) Santa Fe: The Auto biography of a Southwestern Town (Norman: University of Oklahoma Press).
    Book excerpt - (Spidle, Jake W.) Doctors of Medicine in New Mexico (Albuquerque: The University of New Mexico Press).
    Book excerpt - (Parish, William J.) The Charles Ilfeld Company: A Study of the Rise and Decline of Mercantile Capitalism in New Mexico (MA: Harvard U.P.; 1961).
    Biography of Lottie Deno and Edward James Swartz.
  - New Mexico (military): Excerpt - Register of Volunteer Officers from the Headquarters Department of New Mexico, General Orders (no. 21; August 1863). (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - New Mexico (newspapers). (Box 3, Folder 41)
    Excerpts - The Daily New Mexican (various dates: May-June 1870 - 1871).
    Excerpts - Weekly New Mexican (various dates: September - November 1870).
    Book excerpt: (Grove, Pearce S., Becky J. Barnett, and Sandra J. Hansen, eds.) New Mexico Newspapers (NM: University of New Mexico Press).
    Notes written by F. Fierman on various Jewish New Mexico families.
    First page of The Mesilla Times (Saturday March 2, 1861).
    Article - (Simmons, Marc). "The Seligmans: Early Santa Fe Merchants."
  - New Mexico place names. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    Correspondence from R.E. White to F. Fierman (April 30, 1952).
    Definitions of American Indian words from English, Spanish, and Indian languages.
  - New Mexico (Santa Fe- Jews of): Article - (Scholder, David A.) "Reluctant Pilgrims" (October, 1982). (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - New Mexico (Santa Fe- Jews of): Article - (Ayers, John) "A Soldier's Experience in New Mexico" (1884). (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - New Mexico (tapes at Zimmerman Library of the University of New Mexico): Inventory of the archives in the Special Collections Department of Zimmerman Library. (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - New Mexico (taxes): List of persons in the collection district of New Mexico who paid a tax on income of $1,000 or more for the year of 1868. (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Nordhaus family. (Box 3, Folder 47)
    Brief history of the Nordhaus family compiled by Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives.
    Copy of correspondence from Ken Wells to Rabbi Malcolm H. Stern (September 10, 1959).
    Handwritten interview with Robert Nordhaus (December 12, 1990).
  - Nusbaum, Simon. (Box 3, Folder 48)
    Copy of obituary for Simon Nusbaum, postmaster.
    Copy of petition for the appointment of Simon Nusbaum as clerk from the executive office of the Territory of New Mexico (July 31, 1890).
  - Obermayer, Hermann. (Box 3, Folder 49)
    Correspondences between Arthur Obermayer and Melissa Amado (December 1994).
    Correspondences between William Parish and Arthur Obermayer (May 18, 1963).
  - Pick family: Obituary for Elizabeth Pick. (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Polster family. (Box 3, Folder 51)
    Manuscript - "Memories of My Founding Father" (by Edythe Polster).
    "Hiroshige, Mon Amour: An Exhibition Loaned From the Collection of Edythe Polster."
    Pamphlet - (Polster, E.) "From Penzance to Menlo Park" (Pilgrim Press Corporation: N.Y.; 1954).
    Book excerpt - (Polster, E. and M. Fahsbender) Garden Lighting (Pilgrim Press Corporation: N.Y.; 1954).
    Book excerpt - (Polster, E.) "The Story of Johnny One-Light and Mary Even-Glow" (Pilgrim Press).
  - Ravel, Arthur. (Box 3, Folder 52)
    Article - (Braddy, Haldeen) "Pancho Villa At Columbus: The Raid of 1916" (Spring 1965).
    Correspondence from Roy Stivison to F. Fierman (1950, 1951).
    Correspondence from Arthur Ravel to F. Fierman (1961).
    Correspondence from Frederick Katz to Abraham Chanin (June 14, 1991).
    F. Fierman's manuscript notes on the Villa raid on Columbus, 1916.
    Correspondence from Elizabeth Drewry (National Archives) to F. Fierman regarding Villa raid on Columbus (August 3, 1950).
    Genealogy of the Ravel family.